♪〜
〜♪
Speed: 85 iles an hour!
（船員）時速 87アイル
２… ６… ８…
2, 6, 8!
88アイル
88 iles!
残り12分
12 minutes remaining!
おそらく あと10分で
デッドラインを超えます
We will cross the deadline
in 10 minutes!
（Ｂ.Ｄ.ネオン）たった12分間だ
We only have 12 minutes.
華々しく飛ばせよ
Make it fly spectacularly.
（船長）
貴様らも死ぬことになるぞ
You'll die with us!
Do you think so?
（ネオン）そうかね？
We've made our
stopover preparations.
途中下車の準備は出来てる
Here's to a wonderful rendezvous.
すばらしいランデブーを！
フッフッフッフッフッ
ハッハッハッハッハッ
（手下）
いいか？ 赤いコートの金髪野郎だ
Listen up!
He's a blonde in a red coat!
Find him, or else!
なんとしても捜し出せ！
（手下たちの掛け声）
- Get the lead out!
- You, check the engine room!
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
かー！ 敵さんいっぱい
It's crawling with 'em!
This isn't my day.
ツイてないねえ
What'm I gonna do?
どうするよ？ 俺
Hey, you.
（カイト）あんた
ん？
Why did you save me?
あんた なぜ助けた？
Ow!
痛(いて)っ！ ごっ…
You mean
"Thank you for saving me," don't you?!
助けていただいて
ありがとうございましただろ？
Yes, as you said.
（カイト）はい そうでした
So, what are the Baddie Laddies
planning to do?
…で バドラド団のやつらは
何をするつもりなんだ？
Well...
それは…
They're going to drop
the train into the canyon?!
船ごと谷底へ落とす？
もー 勘弁してくれ！
Goddamn! Give me a break!!!
Now I'm sure of it. Death and Poverty
like me so much, they brought friends!
間違いない
俺には死に神か貧乏神が
二桁以上 付いてるんだ
Not to mention
the Insurance Girls!
保険屋のお姉ちゃんズとかもよお！
（カイト）なんでだ？
Why? Why did I say
it was dad's ship?
なぜ あのとき
“父さんの船”だなんて…
Shit!
クソ！
関係ねえじゃねえかよ
What's that good-for-nothing
workaholic got to do with anything?!
あんなワーカホリックの
ろくでなしなんか…
よっしゃー！
じゃ 行くか！
RIGHT ON!!!
Let's get going!!
Go where?
行くって どこへ？
This is no time to fret
over this and that.
あれこれ思い煩ってる
場合じゃないだろ？
You need to reserve
some room in your brain.
脳みその空き容量は
とっとかにゃ
（カイト）ん？
I'm stopping the ship.
（ヴァッシュ）船を止めるんだ
So are you.
お前もやるんだよ！
はい
Yes, sir.
（ヴァッシュ）
おい… こりゃ いったい…
Hey, isn't this?
Yeah. It's the blueprint
of the Flourish.
ああ
フロウリッシュ号の設計図さ
お前… どうしてこんなもんが？
How'd you get this?
It's not the real one.
（カイト）本物じゃねえよ
I copied it from my dad's
workplace when I was a kid.
おやじの仕事場で ガキのころ
おいらが写した物さ
But this is really something...
（ヴァッシュ）
しかし すげえな こりゃ…
It's reproduced down
to the tiny scribbles.
走り書きまで
再現してあるじゃないか
You must have had a lot
of respect for your dad.
尊敬してたんだな
おやじさんのこと
Kaite?
（カイトの父）カイト
Kaite!
カイト
Kaite, become the kind of person
who does things for others.
カイト　人のために
何かを成せる人になりなさい
父さんはサンドスチームを見つけた
For me,
it was the sand steamer.
I wonder what you'll
devote your life to?
お前は これから
何を手に つかんでいくのかな？
（カイトのすすり泣き）
うっ ぐ… チキショウ！
Dammit...
What's there for
someone like me to do?
こんなんで 俺
何(なん)か見つけられんのかな？
ぐっ…
えっ
What are you get-ting...
（ヴァッシュ）な に を
感傷に 浸って るかな？
...all sent-i-men-tal...
...on me for,
you lit-tle squirt?!
こいつは！
目は覚めたか？
Feeling better now?
What?
にゃ…
We're going to survive.
生き残るぞ
GOT THAT?!
いいな！
あ… ああ
Yeah.
（手下たち）フッ
おおおっ おおっ
（銃声）
（手下たち）うああっ
What?
（手下Ａ）何だ？
A dud?
（手下Ｂ）不発か？
That was freakish.
（手下Ｃ）脅かしやがる
（銃声）
（手下たち）うあっ
（手下Ｃ）うあああ ああ…
いいいっ
うんぱっ
（ドアが閉まる音）
（ヴァッシュ）フッフッフッ
ハハッ　大漁 大漁！
What a haul,
what a haul!
At the end,
take a right!
その突き当たりを右
（ドアを開ける音）
（ヴァッシュ）
なるほど　これ全部 伝声管か
I gotcha...
These are all voice tubes?
Yeah, but...
（カイト）でもよ
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
Do you really think
this'll work?
（カイト）
ホントにウマくいくのかな？
The ball is in motion. We just
have to see if they pick it up.
手は打った
あとは 乗ってくれるかどうかだ
ん？
（手下Ｃ）ハアッ ハアッ
He got us, boss!
やられた！ ヘッド
He's not human!
人間業じゃ…
ねえ…
フッ
フフフフフッ
ハハハハッ ハハハハッ…
いいぞ まるで三文小説だ
This is great,
just like a dime novel!
I'm going to see if
he really sparkles!
やつが輝いているかどうか
見せてもらおうじゃねえか！
（ネオン）おい 野郎ども！
Hey, scumbags!
If any of you drag your heels
till time-out, I'll kill you!
時間切れを狙いやがったら
ぶっ殺すぞ！
Bring me the blonde, or else!
金髪野郎を必ず引きずり出せ！
さーて…
A one, and...
I'm at the starboard passenger cabins!
It's him! It's the blonde!!
こちら右舷客室前
出ました！ 金髪です
Good, hold him there.
I'll send help.
（ネオン）
よし　そこで足止めしとけ
すぐ 仲間を向かわす
It's no good! He's hid himself
with incredible speed!!
（ヴァッシュ）ダメです！
あの野郎 ものすごい勢いで
隠れちまいました
AAARGH!
ぐぎゃー！
ぐぎゃああ…
Ham.
お調子者
（カイト）ぐぐっ…
Excellent!
よーし！
Now I'll be able to
guess where they are.
これで
ある程度は敵の動きも分かるよ
But how am I going
to let you know?
だけど
どうやって知らせるんだ？
ん？
Isn't this?
これは…
Talk into it and I'll hear you.
そいつに向かって話しかければ
俺に聞こえる
I don't wanna walk into a bunch
of'em in a narrow passageway.
狭い廊下で
大群と鉢合わせは ごめんだからな
I'm counting on you.
よろしく頼むぜ
Hold on a second!
ち… ちょっと待って
What are you doing with this
lost technology?! Who are you?!
なんだって
こんなロストテクノロジーを—
持ってんだよ？
あんた いったい…
I'd explain it to you...
（ヴァッシュ）
説明してもいいが—
...but you wouldn't believe me,
and there's no time.
きっと お前は信じねえし
時間もない
Anyways, don't worry
about little details!
つうことで
まあ 細かいことは気にすんな
See ya!
じゃあな
あっ
（手下）うああっ
あ… えっ
Vash!
ヴァッシュ
Goddamn! Why does
it start like this?!
チクショウ！ のっけからこれだ
うっ な… なんだよ？
What is it?!
I screwed up.
（ヴァッシュ）
しくじった 出血がひどい
手当てを…
They're bleeding bad!
I have to help them!
うっ
Help them? You mean...
（カイト）手当て？ 手当てって…
Do you mean to tell me...
まさか あんた　今まで
急所を外して撃ち合ってたのか？
...you've been trying not to
kill them the entire time?!
（ヴァッシュ）くっ
わ…
I can't understand you!!
わけ分かんねえよ！
No matter how good a shot you are,
you're going to get yourself killed!
いくら すご腕だからって
そのうち 絶対死ぬぜ あんた
ああっ
ああ…
うっ く…
ううっ
フウッ フウッ
I guess it is kind
of stupid of me.
やっぱ バカみてえか？ 俺
That's true...
そうだよな
It's sloppy.
みっともねえよな
But, you know what?
でもな—
I made a promise.
約束したんだ
If I put out even
one flame of life...
命の火が１つでも消えると—
彼女は きっと悲しむ
...it would make her sad.
Her?
（カイト）彼女？
（手下）おあああっ！
ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ
Hostilities at the
central stairway, 3rd floor!
（手下）中央階段３階脇で交戦中！
Good! Port passenger cabin team,
head round behind the central stairway!
（ベラミィ）よーし！
左舷客室のチーム
中央階段の裏から回り込め！
１階 ５階の各員
そっちは もういい
Everybody on floors 1-5,
leave off activities!
Take positions around
each stairway and close in!
各階段を中心に 配置を狭めろ！
What's our time?
（ネオン）時間は？
Seven minutes left.
（ベラミィ）あと７分です
When you're there, speed across.
They're grouping above and below you.
そこは
そのまま突っ切るほうがいい
上も下も集まってきてるよ
Roger.
（ヴァッシュ）了解
（手下）うん
（銃声）
あいつ
That stupid...
Don't underestimate
the Bad Lad Gang!
バドラド団を甘く見ちゃダメだ！
いや 人間自体を—
No, you've got to stop underestimating
the entire human race!
甘く見すぎちゃダメだよ！
あんたは
Me and them, we've betrayed,
and let lots of people die.
俺も そいつらも
何人も死なせ 何人も裏切ってきた
It's too late for us to go back!
いまさら
元には戻れないんだ
You're too clean!!!
あんたは おキレイすぎるんだ！
ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ
あっ
Then you should start over.
（ヴァッシュ）
なら 仕切り直せばいいだろ
（カイト）え…
Your ticket to the future
is always...
未来への切符は いつも—
白紙なんだ
...blank!
He's broken past the
central engineer's cabin!
（手下）
中央常務室前 突破されました
He's a tough bastard...
（ベラミィ）しぶとい野郎だ
He's good, but he's also
got the Devil's own luck.
腕も立つけど 悪運も強い
What should we do, boss?
（ベラミィ）どうします？ ヘッド
This ain't no luck.
運じゃねえぜ こいつは…
（カイト）
よし　そのまま まっすぐ
Good. Keep going straight.
There should be a stairway
on your right. Take it down.
右手に階段があるはずだ
そこを下へ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
Don't go anywhere else!
That's the only unmanned place.
（カイト）ほかは行っちゃダメだ
そこだけが
なんとか手薄になってる
あっ あ…
（ネオン）
ようこそ パーティー会場へ
Welcome to the party hall.
Were my directions
clear enough for you?
道案内は的確だったかね？
Kaite...
カイト すぐ その部屋から離れろ
...get out of that room, now.
（発砲音）
You sparkle quite well.
Very impressive.
なかなか よい輝き具合だな お前
Are you no longer
afraid of dying?
いまさら 死ぬのなんか怖くねえか
We found him, boss!
It's the kid!
（ベラミィ）
見つけました ヘッド　ガキです
どあっ あ… ううっ
（ベラミィ）ほら 立て！
Get up, you!
You gave us a lot of trouble!
手間かけさせやがって
（カイト）ううっ ぐあっ
万策尽きたな
You're all out of tricks.
Oh, well. It's a real accomplishment
that your impromptu team got this far.
まあ 即席チームで
ここまでやるとは大したもんだ
However, the sad fact is, reality
almost never turns out that beautiful.
しかし 現実が
そう美しく転がらねえのも事実だ
I feel for you.
同情するぜ
（光銃が鳴る音）
Adios.
あばよ
That's far enough.
（メリル･ストライフ）
そこまでですわ
What are you
trying to pull?
何のマネだ？
I'm not particularly
fond of this method...
本来は まるで
趣味じゃないのですけれど—
...but I believed it would be
the easiest way to get past you.
このやり方が あなた方には
一番 通じやすいと思いましたの
I am Meryl Stryfe from
the Bernardelli Insurance Society.
ベルナルデリ保険協会
メリル･ストライフ
I have also been called
Derringer Meryl.
デリンジャー･メリルと
呼ぶ人もおりますわ
（手下）ざけんな この小娘が！
Don't try to mess with us,
little girl!!
（銃声）
（手下たち）どあっ
（手下たちが倒れた音）
Um...
（ミリィ･トンプソン）えっと
私はミリィ･トンプソンと言(ゆ)います
...my name is Milly Thompson.
Let's see...
えっと えっと…
For now, I guess you can call me
Stungun Milly.
一応 スタンガン･ミリィとは
私のことを言(ゆ)います
今日は大目に見ますわ
We'll let you off easy this time.
We don't seem to have a lot of time.
時間もなさそうですしね
Now, act like
a reasonable adult...
節度を持った大人の対応で—
チャッチャっと
片づけちゃってください
...and take care of them quickly,
Mr. Vash the Stampede.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードさん
What?!
（手下たち）なに！
ヴァッシュ･
ザ･スタンピード？
Vash the Stampede?
フッ
（衝撃音）
（悲鳴）
（メリルたち）うわー！
（ネオン）フッ
本当に時間が迫っているらしい
It looks like time is running out.
こんだけ無茶な走りだ
The ship is taking a real beating.
I doubt it'll last that long.
船自体 そう長くはもつまい
どうする？
What do you wanna do?
Wanna go down with me?
一緒に落ちるかい？
I'll drop you right now!
（手下）今 倒してやらあ！
Let's find out just who
sparkles the most between us.
（ネオン）
俺とお前のどっちが輝いてるか
比べようじゃねえか
You thugs stay out of it!
We'll settle it in a duel.
てめえらは手を出すな！
サシの勝負で決めてやる
If I win, will you stop the ship?
俺が勝ったら 船 止めてくれるか？
好きにしな
If you want.
Abnormal heating
in the engine!
（船員）エンジン 異常加熱
船体が悲鳴を上げてます
The hull is screaming!
Now all we can do
is bet on him!
（船長）
今は あいつに かけるしかないんだ
He's our only hope!
あいつに…
I know it's rather trite, but
let's start when this hits the deck.
月並みだが
こいつが甲板に付いたときが
スタートとしよう
All right?
いいな？
（メイルとミリィ）うわー！
（ネオン）派了！
ちいっ！
（銃声）
おあああっ…
ぐふっ
ヴァッシュさん
- Mr. Vash!!
- Are they both hit?!
（ベラミィ）相打ち？
あっ
（光銃が鳴る音）
（ヴァッシュ）うっ…
（銃声）
You idiot...
バカ野郎が！
That's what you get for jumping around
like an acrobat in the shape you're in.
そんなケガで軽業師みてえな
マネするからだ
（ヴァッシュ）フッ
Why don't you finish him? Boss?!
（ベラミィ）
なんで とどめを刺さねえんです？
ヘッド
Shut up!
うるせえ！
He only ripped
his wounds open.
あいつのは
ただ 傷口が開いただけだ
Boss...
（ベラミィ）ヘッド
...you're too soft on people.
You should use those huge dynamos.
あなたは甘すぎですよ
こんなヘビーなダイナモ積んで…
（ネオン）ヘッ
It's like I always say.
いつも言ってんだろう
Nothing shines
like hard-won fame.
命張るから 看板ってのは光るのよ
Vash won!!
（添乗員）ヴァッシュが勝った！
（乗客たち）
やったー！ 助かった
All right!
Hit the brakes! Hurry!!
ブレーキだ！ 急げ！
Yes, sir!
了解
うっ　う…
ああっ
It's no good! They won't engage!
ダメです　作動しません
Did the impact
damage the system?!
衝撃でシステムがイカれたか？
Abnormal rise of pressure
in the boiler!
ボイラー内 圧力が異常上昇
At this rate,
the entire hull will explode!
このままでは
船体ごと爆発してしまいます
Force the engines to stop! Hurry!
機関部を強制停止させろ！ 急げ！
（ヴァッシュ）うっ うう…
You were fighting
in that condition?!
あなた
こんな体で戦ってたんですの？
We have to get that
looked after!
早く傷の手当てを…
Emergency!!
（船員）大変だー！
What's the problem?
（メリル）何ですか？
There's been a system malfunction!
We've lost the steering!
（船員）
シ… システムに異常発生！
操舵(そうだ)不能！
What?!
（メリルとミリィ）ええっ
Kaite...
カイト
Is there a way to
stop the engines?
（船員Ａ）機関を止める方法は？
We have to power down
the system manually!
（船員Ｂ）
手動によるシステムダウンしかない
Where do we do that?
（船員Ｃ）場所は どこだ？
This ship is too old!
この船は古くて分からん
（カイト）第２機関部にあるよ
It's in Engine Room no.2.
There's an emergency stop lever
inside the control system.
制御システムの中に
緊急停止のレバーがある
こ… このガキ！
You little brat!
（カイト）あっ　あああっ
So this is how you did it!
（船員Ｂ）
こんなもの用意してやがったのか！
チクショウ！ チクショウ！
チクショウ！
Damn! Damn!
チクショー！
Damn!!
（カイト）うわっ う…
I'll never forget...
（船員Ｂ）俺は
目の前で仲間が殺されたことを—
...how my crewmate was
killed right in front of me!
絶対に忘れねえ
I won't accept your help.
We'll stop the ship ourselves!
お前の手は借りん
船は俺たちが止める！
Kaite...
（ヴァッシュ）カイト
Kaite.
カイト
What you gonna do, Kaite?
どうするよ？ カイト
Yeah, I know.
分かってるって
I have to pay
for what I've done.
やったことのツケは払わなきゃ
4,500 yarz until deadline!
（アナウンス）
デッドラインまで あと4,500ヤーズ
4,000 yarz remaining!
残り 4,000ヤーズ
ううっ う…
うう…
All right, open it!!
（船員Ａ）よし 開けるぞ
（船員たち）おおっ おおお…
うおっ！
（船員Ａ）うっ うう…
3,500 yarz!
（アナウンス）3,500ヤーズ
3,000
3,000!
Where's the lever?!
（船員Ａ）どこだ？ レバーは
What is this?!
This place is like a cellar!
（船員Ｂ）何だよ これ？
まるで穴蔵じゃねえか
2,500!
（アナウンス）2,500
Look!
（船員Ｃ）見ろ
It's way over there...
あんな所に！
2,000!
（アナウンス）2,000
This isn't working, dammit!
It won't budge!
（船員Ｂ）ダメだ チクショウ！
びくともしねえ
We can't get through
all these pipes!!
パイプだらけで
とてもたどり着けねえぞ
1,800!
（アナウンス）1,800
いけ！
Go.
もうダメだ！ 間に合わねえ！
It's hopeless!
We'll never make it!
Calm down! Think!
落ち着け！ 考えろ 考えるんだ
Think!!
（カイト）どいて！
Move!
うあああ！
うああっ ううっ う…
くっ あ…
ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ
ハアッ ハアッ ハアッ…
うあっ ああっ ああああー！
うあっ！
Emergency stop
system activated!
きょ… 強制停止装置 作動！
How many yarz left?
あと 何ヤーズだ？
800!
（船員）800
It's no good!
ダメだ！
It's too late!!
間に合わない！
おりゃー！
ううっ おりゃー！
ああっ
We were all saved thanks to
Mr. Nasty's selfless act of heroism.
（ヴァッシュ）やっこさんが
身をていしてくれたおかげで—
助かったってわけさ
Neon did that?
（カイト）あのネオンが…
勘違いするな
Don't get the wrong idea.
I just paid off my wager. Next time
we meet, it's no holds barred.
俺は ただ
勝負のツケを払っただけだ
次に会うときは容赦しねえ
I'll take that life
of yours, count on it.
その命 確実に頂くぜ
（ヴァッシュ）フッ
（ヴァッシュ）あの野郎—
That smug jerk lorded it
over us all the way home.
さんざっぱら威張り散らして
帰ってったよ
あっ
（カイト）
♪ So １つ目の夜に
So...
... on the first evening...
... a pebble from somewhere
drops upon the world.
♪ いずこから小石が世界に落ちる
♪ So
So...
（ヴァッシュ）その歌は…
That song!
So it's old! I like it.
悪かったな！ 古い歌で
It's a good song!
いい曲じゃねえかよ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ ああ…
そうそう いい曲だよな
Oh, yeah. It is a good song.
（カイト）
♪ ララ ララララ…
I'm shocked.
（ヴァッシュ）驚いたな
（レムの声）
♪ 小石の子が手を取り
ワルツを描く
... hold hands and compose a waltz.
It's the same song
she loved!
（ヴァッシュ）
彼女が好きだった あの歌だ
（レムの声）
♪ Sound Life
Sound life.
So...
♪ So ３つ目の夜に
... on the third evening...
... the children of the waltz
make waves upon the world.
♪ ワルツの子は世界面(よなも)に…
（鼻をすする音）
（ヴァッシュ）
ぐうっ… クソー 泣けてきた！
Damn!
You're making me cry!
（カイト）いいっ
Dammit, you're making fun of me!!
チキショウ！
バカにしやがったな
Ow! What're you doing to me?!
I'm injured!!
（ヴァッシュ）イッテー！
ケガ人に何すんだよ！
Shut up, you flaky ham!
（カイト）
うるせえ！ このお調子者
（ヴァッシュ）
お お… お調子者だと！
F-F-Flaky ham?!?
（カイト）そうだよ そうだよ
That's right,
you big pork rind!
（ヴァッシュ）お調子者だと！
♪〜
〜♪
I met a lone man
in the desert...
（ヴァッシュ）
砂漠で出会った一人の男
...a traveling priest,
Nicholas D. Wolfwood.
巡回牧師
ニコラスティ･ウルフウッド
He smiled and told me
that I'm a troubled man.
彼は笑って俺に言った
“難儀な男だ”と
Faced with his all-seeing smile,
I could say nothing in my defense.
すべてを見透かしたような
彼の笑顔に—
俺は何も言い返すことが
できなかった
Did I meet this man
because I was destined to?
この男との出会いは運命なのか？
Or was it
a small jest of God?
それとも 神が与えた
ひとときの戯れなのか？
The man's name is
Nicholas D. Wolfwood...
その男の名は
ニコラスティ･ウルフウッド
砂漠で出会った 巡回牧師
...a traveling priest
I met in the desert.